# Adrian Rothschild

San Francisco, CA | LinkedIn | Github | Portfolio

# **SUMMARY**

Experienced Software Engineer, Product Manager, and award-winning Creative Producer with 15 years of combined experience in the Film, TV, and Gaming industries. Past work includes highly acclaimed linear TV and web games for Nickelodeon, PBS Kids, Sesame Workshop, Amazon, and other brands; immersive augmented reality and voice apps; film trailer production and poster design; and prototype digital and physical products.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Makefully

### Web Developer | 2024 - Present

- Developed 8 web games and 3 interactive lesson guides for a STEM education platform. Games built using PixiJS, Spine, JavaScript, and HTML5. Container app built using Vue.js.
- Managed all development stages from concept to launch, with tasks including project management, design, and software development.

#### **Paramount**

### Product Manager (Contract) | 2024

- Managed development and release of an <u>Apple Vision Pro Environment for Paramount+</u> set in the world of Bikini Bottom, celebrating the 25th anniversary of <u>SpongeBob SquarePants</u>.
- Planned and executed an aggressive 4-month development timeline, with beats for ideation, archival pulls, stakeholder reviews, and product integration with the existing Paramount+ VisionOS native app.
- Oversaw all creative decisions on 8 character interactivity moments and a fully featured Jellyfishing minigame.

#### **Primal Screen**

### Web Developer | 2023 - 2024

- Primary developer on <u>Express Yourself with Elmo and Jesse</u>, an art therapy clay creation game for Sesame Workshop.
- Developer on <u>Jelly Ben & Pogo: Babysitting Squee</u>, a narrative game for PBS containing three minigames, each technically complex with multiple levels.
- Developer on <u>Jelly Ben & Pogo: Karaoke</u>, a music game for PBS in which players can customize karaoke songs.

#### **Ever Scouts**

### Technical Project Manager | 2022 – 2023

- Managed workflow for a team of 8 developers and QA engineers, reducing blocked time and increasing sprint velocity.
- Developed agile project plans mapped to waterfall product release timelines, improving transparency to senior leadership on technical progress.
- Delivered company-wide bi-weekly feature update reports, informing relevant teams of product changes and enhancements to improve their workflows.

### Workinman Interactive

### Game Developer | 2022

- Built synchronous multiplayer games for Amazon Glow, a device that allows play between children and remote caregivers via a screen projected onto a play surface.
- Primary developer on a port of Backgammon built all logic & functionality, adapted gameplay to creative feedback, and fixed QA issues.
- Developer on Spidey and His Amazing Friends: Swing into Action built features and fixed QA issues.

# ViacomCBS

### Product Manager, Emerging Products | 2019 – 2021

- Owned product roadmaps for apps and websites serving a range of Paramount brands: Nickelodeon, Nick Jr., Noggin, MTV, Comedy Central, and Paramount+.
- Built relationships with brand partners, creative agencies, development teams, and product vendors to further product development goals.

#### **Nickelodeon**

# Producer, Nickelodeon Sandbox & Emerging Games | 2017 – 2019

- Produced and launched three immersive audio games, featuring characters from *SpongeBob*, *The Loud House*, *Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles*, and other properties, to coincide with the launch of the Amazon Echo Dot Kids Edition.
- Produced a major re-launch of the AR app Do Not Touch, featuring 60+ minigames and new features aligning with Apple & Google's AR Platforms.

### Nickelodeon

# Associate Producer, Noggin | 2016 – 2017

- Produced 10 interactive, 22-minute Play-Along Videos of the show Blaze and the Monster Machines for the relaunch
  of the Noggin app in 2017.
- Managed workflows and gave creative feedback for CG Animation, sound mixing, and software development.

### Out of the Blue

### Production Coordinator | 2015 - 2016

- Coordinated voice-over records and oversaw asset delivery for the second season of the Amazon Kids preschool show Wishenpoof.
- Tracked all creative processes and delivered assets for the Amazon Kids show Creative Galaxy.
- Communicated and routed creative feedback and production deadlines, ensuring on-time studio delivery to Amazon.

### DonorsChoose.org

### Video Producer | 2013 - 2014

- Produced campaign-centric videos in NYC-area public schools to drive donation growth and increase social media presence.
- Produced two of the organization's most shared YouTube videos, featuring teachers and classrooms affected by Hurricane Sandy and Oklahoma tornados.
- Built a cloud-based content management system for the organization to keep track of photo and video assets from public schools throughout the country.
- Managed marketing interns and assistants on media management projects.

### Milestone Film & Video

### Media Designer & Video Editor | 2010 – 2013

- Designed film posters & DVD box covers for theatrical re-releases of independent films: Portrait of Jason (dir. Shirley Clarke), Losing Ground (dir. Kathleen Collins), No Maps on My Taps (dir. George Nierenberg), and others.
- Edited theatrical trailers for The Connection (dir. Shirley Clarke), Come Back, Africa (dir. Lionel Rogosin), Rocco and His Brothers (dir. Luchino Visconti), and others.
- Produced the DVD release of the restored 1959 film Araya (dir. Margot Benacerraf)

# **EDUCATION**

### App Academy

Software Engineering | 2021

#### General Assembly

Product Management | 2019

# Wesleyan University

BA Film Studies | 2008 – 2012 Graduated with Honors

# **AWARDS**

#### Kidscreen Award

Best Game App - Branded | 2020 Do Not Touch (Nickelodeon)

## **Clio Entertainment Award**

Mobile: VR / Augmented Reality | 2019 Do Not Touch (Nickelodeon)

# **SKILLS**

Front End Development, Back End Development, Full Stack Engineering, Product Management, Project Management, Graphic Design, Web Design, Web Development, JavaScript, React, Redux, Ruby, Rails, WordPress, PHP, Squarespace, C#, Node.js, Express.js, Webpack, jQuery, Git, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, RSpec, Flux, Sass, AJAX, AWS, JSON, Websockets, Webhooks, VS Code, Omniture, Google Analytics, JIRA, Confluence, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Premiere, Adobe After Effects, Miro, Airtable, Github, Heroku, Unity, Final Cut Pro, Avid Media Composer, Creative Problem Solving, Leadership, Empathy, Patience, Time Management, Strategic Thinking, Communication, Collaboration, Adaptability